The Rider is a drama, western film directed by Chloé Zhao.
Once a rising star of the rodeo circuit, and a gifted horse trainer, young cowboy Brady is
warned that his riding days are over after a horse crushed his skull at a rodeo.
In an attempt to regain control of his own fate, Brady undertakes a search for a new
identity and what it means to be a man in the heartland of the United States.
Brady Blackburn, played by Brady Jandreau.
Wayne Blackburn, played by Tim Jandreau.
Lilly Blackburn, played by Lilly Jandreau.
Cat Clifford, played by Cat Clifford.
Terri Dawn Pourier, played by Terri Dawn Pourier.
Lane Scott, played by Lane Scott.
The Rider is a 2017 American contemporary western film
written, produced and directed by Chloé Zhao.
The film stars Brady Jandreau, Lilly Jandreau, Tim Jandreau, Lane Scott, and
Cat Clifford and was shot in the Badlands of South Dakota.
It premiered in the Directors' Fortnight section at the Cannes Film
Festival on May 20, 2017, where it won the Art Cinema Award.
It was released in theaters in the United States on April 13, 2018.
It grossed $4.2 million and was critically praised for its story, performances, and
the depiction of the people and events that influenced the film.
The film explores themes of rodeo, horseback riding,
horse, riding accident, head injury.
The tone is emotional.